<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Desert Tropics Custom pools - Articles</title>
    <description>Your latest Desert Tropics news</description>
    <link></link>
    
      
        <item>
          <title>What's the Difference Between Project Management and PSA?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re often tasked with explaining the difference between project management and professional services automation (PSA) when it comes to our business management solution. While each aspect serves a unique purpose and has a highly distinct audience, they both deliver the same benefits to small to mid-sized businesses (SMBs)- streamlined operations, improved business insights, increased productivity within the organization and, most importantly, increased profitability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Benefits of Project Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As SMB owners face increasing demands on their time and resources (people, tools &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; money) while trying to run a successful company, they have little time to fine-tune operations to gain that all-important differentiation within their respective industries. For this reason, project management tools are starting to gather steam within the SMB market – especially considering less than a third of all projects were completed on time and on budget during the past year. In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.softwareadvice.com/project-management/buyerview/web-based-smb-report-2015/&quot;&gt;recent Software Advice survey&lt;/a&gt;, 70 percent of prospective buyers currently use manual methods for their project management. One can see why less than 33 percent of projects crossed the finish line on time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/product/&quot;&gt;project management tools&lt;/a&gt;, companies – especially professional services organizations (PSOs) like marketing and advertising agencies – have a better view of where all current projects stand at any given time. This oversight is enabled through real-time access to project statuses, keeping owners and managers in the know and eliminating the exhausting task of chasing down update after update across teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With better project insight, business owners can more effectively staff projects, improve budgeting and forecasting and easily recognize areas of growth – and areas of improvement – within the company. All of these capabilities help owners and managers better capture billing, identify more profitable projects for the organization, better service clients and, in the long-run, more effectively scale the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, what &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; PSA?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core, PSA includes aspects of project management, plus quite a bit of added functionality. As the name denotes, it manages and automates a number of professional services such as accounting, help desk and ticketing, customer relationship management (CRM) and time and expense tracking, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PSAs integrate with popular business software like QuickBooks to further optimize and automate processes. This ensures that businesses are not only capturing billable time and expenses more accurately in accordance with contracts and service level agreements (SLAs), but the billing and invoicing process is seamless – and painless – for SMB owners. A PSA solution also helps route the right person to the right project, helping increase customer satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PSOs such as IT consultants and software services, managed service providers (MSPs) and value added resellers (VARs) notice a marked decrease in the time spent on business operations once they implement a PSA solution. This single integrated view of the entire company’s operations provides an invaluable snapshot of how the organization is performing against benchmarks and, similar to project management, helps owners and managers identify areas of improvement and growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With revenue growth slowing for SMBs – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20140211005597/en/SPI%C2%A0Research-Professional-Services-Industry-Growth-Profit-Decline#.VS6PCGYqp-U&quot;&gt;it fell to just 10% in 2013&lt;/a&gt;, down from 11.5% the previous year – a business management platform that combines aspects of both project management and PSA can help companies push to that next level. By automating time-consuming processes and providing a high-level overview of company operations, project management and PSA tools allow company owners and managers to concentrate on delivering continuous service improvement and strategically growing the business. Who wouldn’t rather be out chasing their dreams than a status report?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re not already a customer, what are you waiting for? Sign up for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/free-trial/&quot;&gt;14-day free trial&lt;/a&gt; to see what your life can be like when you start chasing your dreams instead of a status report.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-04-22T03:26:00+00:00</pubDate>
          <link>/blog/whats-the-difference-between-project-management-and-psa/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/whats-the-difference-between-project-management-and-psa/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>5 Time-saving Tools for Agency Owners</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;You show up to work and the office phone rings. Your cell phone is constantly buzzing with beeps and notifications, and when you open your email, it’s flooded with a seemingly never-ending stream of new messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flipping to your calendar is no better because your entire day is booked back-to-back with internal and client-facing meetings. Not to mention, the end of the month is approaching which means it’s time to calculate expenses, bill clients and pay out employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running a service-based agency is hard work, which is why most successful agency owners rely on time-saving tools to streamline day-to-day processes and stay organized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are five automation tools that keep busy agency owners organized and on track for success:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project management software&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project management software facilitates easy communication between  team members regarding the specifics of project schedules, timelines, budgets, expenses and other critical information that’s relevant to decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The software works by capturing project vitals in one space so that important items don’t end up lost on sticky notes, in email chains and individual filing systems. Business owners and project managers gain a holistic view of projects and are able to communicate with team members and keep an eye on project updates without the need for meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also enables team members to access information about a project in a single location. Increased transparency – in comparison to emails, memos and traditional meetings – makes it easier for project managers to receive feedback and input from the entire team. Finally, project management software speeds the pace of work and increases decision-making agility by giving everyone real-time updates on project statuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time and expense tracking applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agency owners who are able to accurately predict how much time their team is spending on projects are also able to accurately predict the amount of new work their teams can take on, as well as how long that new work will take to complete. This results in the ability to better estimate quotes, staffing needs and profit margins–a prerequisite to an agency’s success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of estimating the time it takes to complete a project, agency owners can use a time and expense tracking application to automate guesswork and immediately increase billing accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s more, the accuracy of a time and expense tracking tool gives agency owners insight into how much work their team can perform in a given amount of time. This information can be used to estimate the price of future projects and the resource allocation needs of the agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Billing and invoicing software&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Billing clients can be time consuming when expense tracking isn’t executed accurately. The most fitting billing and invoicing applications integrate with time and expense tracking applications to automatically tally hours as expenses at the end of a pay period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Billing and invoicing software saves agency owners time – and perhaps more importantly, it gives agency owners peace of mind – by automatically calculating and organizing debts and assets. Billing and invoicing software also more accurately captures hours and expenses across projects and accounts, which helps avoid situations related to over- and under-billing clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resource allocation features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within project management software, agency owners should look for resource allocation tools such as scheduling and resource measurement. While it’s useful to have a place to view up-to-date project progress, the best way to save time is to allocate the use of future time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resource measurement tools like time and expense reporting allow team leaders to predict what they will need for future projects in the way of man-hours. Scheduling tools then allow agency leaders to allocate those hours by assigning tasks to individual team members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resource allocation features save money by enabling agency leaders to plan ahead both in terms of the project and financially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer relationship management system&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customer relationship management (CRMs) systems organize and track lead and customer interactions, sales processes, marketing efforts, customer service and technical support interactions. CRMs automate sales workflows, help utilize standards in account management and establish a consistent marketing process. Through organization alone, they save agency owners time and provide insight into the lifecycle of a customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CRMs also give agency owners insight into the best time to contact prospects and who their most profitable clients are. That information gives decision makers the ability to optimize the use of their resources by only contacting prospects when it will advance a sale, for example. Ultimately, CRMs help agency owners streamline time management by quantifying the value of client interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business owners are busy, and monitoring project progress via meetings isn’t the best use of time. Not to mention, allocating resources is tricky when expenses are estimated. This is where project management software comes in to help agency owners streamline communications and stay caught up on project progress without needing to attend every meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time and expense tracking tools, billing and invoicing software, scheduling applications and CRMs make it possible for agency owners to precisely allocate their resources and plan ahead financially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make the most of today’s business management tools to save time and money and increase the efficiency of your overall organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re not already a customer, what are you waiting for? Sign up for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/free-trial/&quot;&gt;14-day free trial&lt;/a&gt; to see what your life can be like when you start chasing your dreams instead of a status report.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-04-21T03:43:00+00:00</pubDate>
          <link>/blog/5-time-saving-tools-for-agency-owners/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/5-time-saving-tools-for-agency-owners/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Leveraging Project Management for Effective Company Growth</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly every business has a need to increase their operational efficiency. Through the use of effective software, companies streamline many tasks that previously required an entire department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Efficient processes increase productivity and collaboration, establish values through prioritization, optimize resource allocation, and free up company leaders to spend time growing the business rather than managing day-to-day operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few aspects of project management routinely act as bottlenecks or waste resources. By improving or automating them, company leaders can spend more time growing the business than they spend worrying whether it’s running properly. With a closer eye on project management, the entire organization can run more smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better Financial Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cutting wasteful spending can lead to money allocation in more profitable areas. Your products can reach customers quickly during peak demand and more customers can be attracted. High revenue mixed with low costs equals enhanced profitability and overall cash flow. It’s important to keep in mind, however, that money is not “wasted” when it’s spent on equipment and resources that do not contribute to profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creates Value&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When managers are more focused on generating new business versus directly managing the daily operations of an organization, it creates new value for the company. With every new client or account, managers are generating money for the company, which increases overall profits. Streamlining operational tasks frees managers’ time to focus on creating value for the company and bringing in new money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eliminates Waste&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many instances, streamlining daily operations allows new, more efficient processes and procedures to emerge. As a result, the old inefficient procedures are replaced, thus cutting waste in many departments and saving the company money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waste elimination plus value creation equates to a significant increase in profits. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/greatspeculations/2015/03/04/ups-margins-to-improve-with-increased-operational-efficiency/&quot;&gt;Forbes Magazine&lt;/a&gt; reported that shipping giant UPS is in the process of implementing new navigation software that will cut the distance traveled by UPS drivers by more than 100 million miles annually. This is an example of eliminating waste while improving both finances and gas and truck usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Faster Response Times&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More efficient daily operations result in quicker response times, allowing your company to be more flexible and adaptable. When organizations have streamlined processes, they can adapt production instantly to satisfy customer requirements while still maintaining a profit. When a last-minute project pops up, response times are much faster and employees are more agile and able to allocate resources to that project immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improve Productivity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, because streamlining reduces waste, it frees up employees’ time to focus on more important tasks within their respective departments. Improved employee productivity enables your entire organization to check more tasks and projects off that to-do list. Again, this leads to an increase in cost savings and profits. At the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.traveldailymedia.com/218956/amadeus-solutions-streamline-operations-at-munich-airport/&quot;&gt;Munich Airport&lt;/a&gt;, new software technology has reduced runway waiting times by 50 percent by unlocking airport capacity and reducing slot wastage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increase Collaboration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, when wasteful processes are cut and free up more of management’s time, it becomes much easier to collaborate on major decisions. The good news is, the collaboration doesn’t stop with internal departments. Collaboration increases among suppliers, customers and partners, thus increasing the flow of communication. Technology allows managers to collaborate with new clients who may be across the globe, too, saving travel costs and time without sacrificing outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Streamlining daily operations delivers a number of benefits across the board. Saving time, money and resources while cutting waste and increasing internal and external collaboration fosters better and quicker business decisions while improving profitability. Plus, there’s always the added bonus of enabling management to spend less time chasing down status reports and more time strategically growing the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re not already a customer, what are you waiting for? Sign up for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/free-trial/&quot;&gt;14-day free trial&lt;/a&gt; to see what your life can be like when you start chasing your dreams instead of a status report.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-04-16T03:58:00+00:00</pubDate>
          <link>/blog/leveraging-project-management-for-effective-company-growth/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/leveraging-project-management-for-effective-company-growth/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Tips for Scaling a Rapidly Growing Business</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Simply starting a business is the most difficult step toward success. But growing that business is a very close second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While growth should always be on your mind, ensuring that the growth is steady and consistent helps you allocate proper resources and manage said expansion. If the growth is too fast, you might not be prepared. If the growth begins rapidly, then slows down, you might have employees who are underutilized. Being prepared to scale for any type of growth that you could encounter is a critical success factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The greatest issue facing service-based businesses when attempting to scale is the ability to operate twice as fast as the competition while maintaining a high level of quality. There are many methods of scaling your business for growth; however, the most effective include: appreciate your employees, build an effective management team, develop a cash-flow strategy, enact transparency and accountability, implement valuable project management software, and utilize exceptional organizational skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appreciate your Employees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your employees are the lifeblood of your company, so make sure that potential new hires are passionate about the industry. This passion and enthusiasm is especially important during periods of rapid growth, as it allows them to hit the ground running and provides the fuel needed to help drive company growth. Once you have excellent employees, treat them as equals and entrust them with company vision and goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build an Effective Management Team&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most entrepreneurs note that the greatest asset that saved their companies was bringing in the right people to fill in any skills gaps and establish internal systems and processes immediately. By constructing an efficient and effective management team from the start, you can better prepare for the rapid growth that occurs during scaling. You’ll be able to delegate responsibilities to this management who can make decisions on day-to-day operations that have an impact on the overall business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Develop a Cash-Flow Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintaining a steady cash flow is critical to the overall health of your company. Paying bills (and employees) in a timely fashion and purchasing materials help ensure that your services can properly scale. Therefore, it is critical to develop and maintain a cash-flow strategy to ensure you have enough money during slow periods but, even more importantly, have enough cash on hand during periods of rapid growth. This will help comfortably scale the business and allow for future growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement Valuable Project Management Software&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Effective project management software can help you and your team automate many tasks, thus freeing everyone up to perform more value-added activities. This could include generating more business, improving the overall quality of services, or several other critical functions that contribute to the success of your business. Freeing up management’s time will also allow them to prepare and maintain the company during growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Utilize Exceptional Organization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excellent project management software can also significantly improve organization, which will enhance the customer experience. When better organized, the company operates much more smoothly and efficiently. During periods of considerable growth, remaining organized will ensure you can advance scalability efficiently and effectively to maximize profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Effectively scaling up a service-based business can be a challenge. However, with the proper tools, resources, preparation and planning, you can experience steady growth and overall success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re not already a customer, what are you waiting for? Sign up for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/free-trial/&quot;&gt;14-day free trial&lt;/a&gt; to see what your life can be like when you start chasing your dreams instead of a status report.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-04-14T03:31:00+00:00</pubDate>
          <link>/blog/tips-for-scaling-a-rapidly-growing-business/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/tips-for-scaling-a-rapidly-growing-business/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>5 Things Your Competitors Can Teach You About Project Management</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;When managing your company projects, there are several factors you have to balance to achieve success – overvaluing any single aspect can throw your entire team askew. Your best competitors embrace the discipline of balance. Asking yourself, “What’s their secret?” can lead to methods and techniques you can learn from your competitors to make your company projects more successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unified Information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One trait your most successful competitors embody is unified project information. A company using out-of-date practices or older project management software can find its project data fragmented. Thus the project manager is left dealing with inaccurate, piecemeal information, making it a lot harder to accurately and successfully execute. If you want to keep pace with the market, you need &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/product/&quot;&gt;a unified approach to market data collection and sharing said information&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;** Cloud Computing**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best companies are the ones thinking ahead. Cloud computing has become the latest trend in business technology. With cloud-based platforms, business information is stored online and can be accessed by end users via desktops, laptops, even smartphones when they need it. This not only keeps everyone on the same platform, it also lets them unify and share project information from any location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;** Real-Time Information Updates**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business moves fast. When a new product launches, you need to deliver and receive market information that is accurate and up-to-date. A unified project management software application ensures that important market information and sales trends are reported company-wide and from all corners of the world where you have agents or offices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;** An Organized Approach**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many projects fail before they even begin. As noted in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/business_technology/delivering_large-scale_it_projects_on_time_on_budget_and_on_value&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; by McKinsey &amp;amp; Company in conjunction with the University of Oxford, “17% of IT projects go so bad that they can threaten the very existence of the company. These unpredictable high-impact events–‘black swans’ in popular risk parlance–occur significantly more often than would be expected […].” Your successful competitors are taking the necessary steps to mitigate the risk of this happening. The root causes of such catastrophic errors often occur due to under-planning or presenting a project work plan lacking in details and concrete figures. Project management software can supply the data you need to make a project plan based off of exact market data, so your project has a better chance of succeeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project management software also increases transparency and makes it easier to catch errors early on in a project. When information is published where all project members can see it, feedback is easier to give and receive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;** Correct Allocation Of Company Resources**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last thing you can learn from your competitors is correct allocation of company resources. As noted a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techrepublic.com/article/avoid-these-common-causes-for-project-failure/&quot;&gt;Techrepublic&lt;/a&gt; article, “This covers a lot of areas. You may not have the right level of resources because you didn’t estimate the work correctly.” This is why a coherent plan is essential. By planning out the project process in detail, you can correctly allocate the needed resources and avoid waste and inefficiency. Note that resources does not just mean money; it also covers company equipment and personnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The success of a project often hinges on information organization. Modern business management software can help you organize your company projects and keep mission-critical information front and center. By embracing the above techniques and combining them with a trusted, robust project management solution, the success of your competitors will no longer be so mysterious, and you can start seeing the same success in your own project management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re not already a customer, what are you waiting for? Sign up for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/free-trial/&quot;&gt;14-day free trial&lt;/a&gt; to see what your life can be like when you start chasing your dreams instead of a status report.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-04-10T03:58:00+00:00</pubDate>
          <link>/blog/5-things-your-competitors-can-teach-you-about-project-management/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/5-things-your-competitors-can-teach-you-about-project-management/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>9 Quick Tips About Gaining Visibility Into Your Team's Efficiency</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;When managing your team, one key to success is efficiency. Wasted time and a lack of overall productivity not only cost the company money, but can also slow down projects and cause friction within your team. Here are nine tips to help you successfully track and measure your team’s efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Much Work Is Being Completed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s tempting to look at the hours your team works and conclude things are going well just by the number of hours put toward projects. However, this does not mean time is being used effectively. Measure your team not by time, but by the tasks that are being completed and by their value to your organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;** Project Timeframe**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a no-brainer, but projects should be finished on time. If your team is constantly behind or late, then the efficiency of each individual and the process as a whole should be observed and re-evaluated. The problem could be assigning tasks to under-qualified employees, or it could be a lack of appropriate timeframe allocation for projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;** Expenses**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One component of efficacy is the overall expense of a project. By tracking your expenses, you can make sure the ROI is paying off, money isn’t going to waste and that projects are not running over balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;** Use Of Resources**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important metric to measure your team’s efficiency is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/agency-challenges-scaling-project-management/&quot;&gt;how they are using resources&lt;/a&gt;. This includes employees, company time, money, and equipment. If a high amount of company resources is going toward a team, and they are yielding low results, then overall they are not efficient and you might reconsider how you’re allocating and managing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;** The Bottom Line**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep your eye on the bottom line. A lot of management fails by getting wrapped up in micromanagement and losing sight of overall company goals. You can’t manage every piece of data, and you will gain more useful results by tracking data streams that &lt;em&gt;directly&lt;/em&gt; influence your team and are of utmost importance (i.e. profitability).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;** Response To Customers**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your business, you might have varying degrees of customer interaction. However, reacting to customer questions or concerns can be a good measure of team efficacy. Are concerns being addressed, what are the customers saying, and what are the concerns being raised? If common issues continue to come up, it’s time to dig deeper into your customer-facing messaging and procedures to search for a more impactful process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;** Customer Feedback**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related to the above, be sure to get feedback from your customers. Make sure customers are pleased with your official responses, and that issues are addressed in a proper timeframe. Avoiding recurrent issues and common complaints is a sign that your work and efforts are yielding positive results. If you receive negative feedback, listen. Use it as a starting point for an investigation into how to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;** Read Reports**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern business software can provide a wide variety of metrics. One of the best ways to track your team’s efficiency is to run regular reports and compare the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;relevant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; figures. Positive trends can point to effective efficiency practices while negative ones could be signs a change is needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;** Ask For Updates**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep tabs on your team. Set goals for them and ask about progress. You can measure their statements on what tasks they’re completing versus the hard data you have already collected to gauge their true workload and efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a multitude of data points you can use to truly understand your team’s efficiency. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/product/&quot;&gt;Project management software&lt;/a&gt; allows you to more easily gather this data. Once implemented, not only do you have a clearer picture, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keyedin.com/keyedinprojects/article/5-simple-ways-to-improve-employee-utilization-and-productivity/&quot;&gt;but as noted in a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keyedin.com/keyedinprojects/article/5-simple-ways-to-improve-employee-utilization-and-productivity/&quot;&gt;KeyedIn article&lt;/a&gt;, “improving your resource deployment upfront should not only improve your future resource productivity and utilization, it will also give you a more realistic view of the health of the organization by comparing planned versus actual.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re not already a customer, what are you waiting for? Sign up for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/free-trial/&quot;&gt;14-day free trial&lt;/a&gt; to see what your life can be like when you start chasing your dreams instead of a status report.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-04-08T03:05:00+00:00</pubDate>
          <link>/blog/9-quick-tips-about-gaining-visibility-into-your-teams-efficiency/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/9-quick-tips-about-gaining-visibility-into-your-teams-efficiency/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>7 Common Misconceptions About Project Management</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost all employees have an opinion about project management, and more often than not, it is an unfavorable view. On its own, project management is not an activity that’s directly tied to revenue, making it easy to form misconceptions about the role of project management, especially when its aims are not clearly communicated to team members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at some of the misconceptions surrounding project management. Though our list is long, don’t be discouraged – there’s a solution! One of the best ways to debunk misconceptions like these is to have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/&quot;&gt;centralized communication system&lt;/a&gt; that keeps all team members apprised of project aims and developments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project management is unnecessary overhead&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time spent on planning a project might appear to be a waste of resources and a significant delay to the more tangible work involved. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.corporatecomplianceinsights.com/top-five-project-management-myths/&quot;&gt;Project Management Institute&lt;/a&gt;, organizations employing robust project management processes out-perform those that don’t in three major ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On-time delivery is 28% higher&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Within-budget delivery is 24% higher&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Goal achievement is 20% higher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project managers are just paper pushers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people involved with a project misunderstand the project manager’s role when visible activities seem only to be comprised of developing project plans, resource schedules, endless status updates, and compiling meeting notes. The real value of a good project manager is in the value he or she adds to meetings and negotiations, being a mentor and counselor, and in being the project champion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The process is the most important part of a project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an in-depth report on talent management, the Project Management Institute, cited organizations’ &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pmi.org/learning/pm-network/2014/debunking-common-project-myths.aspx#sthash.nha8UZXs.dpbs&quot;&gt;growth and profitability&lt;/a&gt; as being directly attributable to the employee talent pool rather than company processes. The report demonstrates that the shortage in available talent has reduced project quality by 31%, inhibited and lessened innovation by 29%, and caused the cancellation of important initiatives by 27% more than a comparable talent-rich period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Execution is the top priority&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Racing ahead with the execution of a project is a difficult temptation to resist, but to get high-quality results, speed cannot be the top priority. Project management experts agree that without proper planning, it is more than likely that a project will require significant rework, which in turn causes frustration for the team, missed milestones, and probable overruns in budget and time. Execution without sufficient planning that uncontrollably runs off course like a house fire, very often leads directly to expensive and time-consuming fire-fighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After risk assessment, race to the finish line&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the initial risk assessment, many projects fail to make risk review part of ongoing meetings and evaluations, but new and unconsidered risks always pop up in the course of a longer project. If project risk is not periodically revisited as a potential factor influencing completion milestones, the chances increase that the unexpected will occur and the entire schedule will be thrown into chaos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No project should ever be abandoned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a significant amount of work and resources has been poured into a project, it’s only natural that management and team members are reluctant to pull the plug and scrap the initiative. Doubtless, it will be an embarrassment to company managers and executives, but when the original need for the project has vanished and the project no longer makes sense, further investment is simply unjustifiable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once budgets are locked in, new project ideas must wait until next year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a formula for losing good ideas and having them simply fall off the radar. In companies where managers regularly submit project ideas for the improvement of the business, it might be better to establish a rolling review of these ideas to get visibility for them and ensure that they are not lost before next year’s budget meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project management matters immensely — it guides the productivity and ultimately, the success of an organization. Consider these myths when approaching your next project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re not already a customer, what are you waiting for? Sign up for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/free-trial/&quot;&gt;14-day free trial&lt;/a&gt; to see what your life can be like when you start chasing your dreams instead of a status report.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-04-06T03:48:00+00:00</pubDate>
          <link>/blog/7-common-misconceptions-about-project-management/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/7-common-misconceptions-about-project-management/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Change Your Business with New Vorex Features</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;At Vorex, our development team never sleeps. We’re continually refining our solution to deliver the absolute best online PSA and project management features to help busy business owners streamline day-to-day operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, we released even more functions designed to empower your business. In addition to your &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/product/&quot;&gt;favorite Vorex features&lt;/a&gt; like invoicing, billing, service desk and ticketing and time tracking, our cloud-based solution now also includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Native CRM&lt;/strong&gt; - New dashboards for better visibility into your clients, opportunities and sales pipeline, plus one-click conversion of opportunities into projects and contracts and a new quotation module that enables you to create and email quotes from within the CRM module. We’ve also added several new reports for prospects and clients.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Search Employees by Skill –&lt;/strong&gt; Easily find the most qualified employee for a project, saving you time and improving customer service.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Reports&lt;/strong&gt; – In addition to the CRM Reports, there are new Project Reports for improved project insight and Reimbursements Summary and Detail Reports to help track your employees’ expenses and reimbursements.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resource Utilization Screen –&lt;/strong&gt; An interactive display that shows your employees’ utilization level over a week, month and year period. Now you don’t have to guess who is busy and who needs more work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Expenses Insight within Projects&lt;/strong&gt; - Project managers can add Expenses to Projects dashboards, enabling better financial insight for projects. The Financial Tab within the Projects dashboard has also been enhanced, including critical budgeting information such as used/remaining hours, expenses, budgets and billing revenue details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of the new features of Vorex’s latest release that have the power to change your business, your life and your world through simplified PSA and project management. If you’re logged into Vorex, click on “About” to see the full list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have lots of exciting developments on the roadmap for later this quarter (can you say multi-currency, Gantt Charts for multiple projects, integrations with RMM tools and backup vendors, among others?). You won’t want to miss what we have in store!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not already a customer, what are you waiting for? Sign up for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/free-trial/&quot;&gt;14-day free trial&lt;/a&gt; to see what your life can be like when you start chasing your dreams instead of a status report.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-04-01T11:20:54+00:00</pubDate>
          <link>/blog/change-your-business-with-new-vorex-features/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/change-your-business-with-new-vorex-features/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Introducing Vorex Winter Edition 2015</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Daylight Saving Time brings with it the promise of spring, warmer temps and longer days. And this year, it has delivered Vorex Winter Edition 2015!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winter Edition 2015 is the biggest release since launching our service desk offerings in December 2014. The latest product release is designed to help users of our online professional services automation (PSA) and project management solution get even more out of their day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that 46 percent of small business leaders spend more than a third of their day on operational tasks like project management, billing and invoicing instead of strategy, sales and new product development? With Vorex Winter Edition, the time spent on business operations and effectively managing day-to-day operations is dramatically reduced, enabling you to move your business forward – and get out and enjoy life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New in Vorex Winter Edition 2015&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quickbooks® Online Integration&lt;/strong&gt;: Quickly and easily transfer billable time directly from Vorex Time Tracking to create invoices and bill clients.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Native CRM Features:&lt;/strong&gt; Track current accounts, service desk tickets, contacts and new revenue opportunities from within Vorex’s native CRM, or integrate directly with leading SFA and CRM systems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calendar Integration&lt;/strong&gt;: Fully functional company calendar to easily schedule projects, tasks, to-dos and appointments, as well as dispatch team members due to visibility into their schedules. Vorex now simply and easily synchronizes with each user’s individual Outlook calendar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Employee HR Profiles&lt;/strong&gt;: Add skills, skill categories and education profiles for employees to easily track technology and business skills, as well as educational profiles, for employees to better align them with incoming projects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated Online Project Management Dashboard&lt;/strong&gt;: Improved project insight with widgets, statistics and charts in a single location to enable a holistic and immediate overviews of your business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a number of other new features and enhancements, as well as a new expense report, in Vorex Winter Edition 2015. If you’re logged into Vorex, click on “About” to see the full list. Plus, all of your favorite &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/product/&quot;&gt;Vorex features&lt;/a&gt; are still here – from Time Tracking to Project Management to Help Desk and Ticketing – to help you change your business, change your life and change your world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give the new features a spin to see just how much easier Vorex Winter Edition 2015 will make your online PSA and project business management. Not a customer? Now’s the perfect time to sign up for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/free-trial/&quot;&gt;free 14-day trial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-03-12T07:00:43+00:00</pubDate>
          <link>/blog/introducing-vorex-winter-edition-2015/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/introducing-vorex-winter-edition-2015/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>A Growing Agency&amp;#8217;s Biggest Challenge: Scaling Project Management</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was written by Leah Nurik, President of Gabriel Marketing Group. It first appeared on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gabrielmarketing.com/2015/03/growing-agencys-biggest-challenge-scaling-project-management/&quot;&gt;Gabriel Marketing Group&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been lucky at Gabriel Marketing Group (GMG). We’ve grown quickly and steadily, year over year. To be clear, I don’t say that to brag about our success – a lack of humility is a sure fire “jinx” in my worldview, where superstition and dread are often far too present for idleness or over confidence. Instead, I say it to let you know that although we have grown significantly and quickly, the road to today has not always been a rose-lined Easy Street. Scaling a growing professional services organization is, well, frankly, super, duper flipping hard. And, I know we are not the only ones facing that challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scale challenges aren’t unique to agencies, of course. We are a technology marketing company specializing in start-ups and high-growth B2B software companies. Our clients grow fast, and, often, get acquired. Knowing that is our sweet spot, we see companies that struggle to scale effectively and successfully all the time. And, if they can do it all while actually making money, they’ve attained the Holy Grail. However, our clients, for the most part, are product companies, and that is very different than the agency model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primarily, most – if not all-agencies derive the majority of revenue from fulfilling service contracts, whether those contracts are based on hours or scope, project or retainer. Agencies need real, live talented people to fulfill contracts. And, in the GMG world, we need really, awesome, incredibly smart, fun, creative and dedicated people to do it right and keep clients coming back for more. (Looking for a job? We’re hiring!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, some agencies resell some software and mark up ad buys for incremental revenue, but usually, the revenue generated is a pittance compared to retainers and project work. Agencies don’t sell products, which means their ability to scale well is contingent upon their ability to find awesome people-which is very hard-and, manage projects and tasks succinctly and efficiently, deliver good work, and make a solid enough margin that they can invest BACK into the business to hire more people and start the cycle again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound easy? If you think it is, you are way smarter than me. I think it’s hard-really hard. I’ve learned a lot along the way, and one piece of advice I can give to growing agency owners – from marketing to digital to design and others – is to bite the bullet and invest in cloud-based business and project management software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The right cloud-based project management software will let you manage all your ongoing projects, allocate resources, has a built-in time tracker, manage inventory (if you are selling through hardware), integrate with accounting and billing software such as QuickBooks for billing, and more. After all is said in done, having a complete cohesive view of what your people are doing, how much time they have, their margin and what tasks and projects are the most profitable, you can crash through the ceiling of complexity to grow to the next level. The right project management software can change your strategy, and completely change your business-not to mention the stress level of the agency owner or partner who is craving constant insight and lacking the desire to micromanage the crack team of employees she fought so hard to find, cultivate and train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At GMG, we started off with Basecamp when we were super small-one of our clients introduced us. But Basecamp, although good for a very early stage company (and cheap – yay!), lacks the features required for true cloud-based project management, including resource utilization, integrations, CRM-integrations or native-service desk, and automated invoicing. Then, we snagged Vorex as a client. Originally created for Managed Service Providers (MSPs) who needed Professional Services Automation (PSA), Vorex was looking to continue to build out PSA software features and also target the online project management space. So, we are helping them do that. And, in the process, we are now a client and it is helping us change the business by allowing our team members to get more done, faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vorex and other online project management providers have designed their products with the growing small business and boutique agency in mind. That means, completeness with simplicity to help us scale, fast. Vorex also debuted its new brand this week – in full disclosure, yes, we created it (and we love it!). Check it out at www.vorex.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-03-04T14:44:13+00:00</pubDate>
          <link>/blog/agency-challenges-scaling-project-management/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/agency-challenges-scaling-project-management/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Can Business Management Software Prevent Failure?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;SMBs are critical to the U.S. economy. Small businesses represent approximately half the private sector, and medium-sized businesses represent roughly one third, according to the Small Business Administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ensuring that SMBs succeed can be an uphill battle. They face a unique set of challenges that can often be overcome through sound business practices bolstered by business management tools. Here are three common reasons SMBs fail and how a great business management platform can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working Harder, Not Smarter&lt;/strong&gt; — Not properly allocating your resources on projects and tasks that help move your company forward is a common mistake many growing companies make. Without proper insight into who is working on which projects and how much of their time is spent on each can introduce crippling operational inefficiencies. A business management platform can help you examine KPIs and determine if your employees are being over- or underutilized, for example.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using Outdated Tools to Manage Growth&lt;/strong&gt; — While business growth is the dream of every SMB, it creates new challenges, particularly when it comes to technology. Managing a company with a notebook and Excel spreadsheet isn’t scalable, especially for a business that grows from servicing 10 customers to 100 or more. Implementing technology and processes that better manage resource utilization, billing and finances can help you better accommodate company and customer growth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not Capturing All Billings&lt;/strong&gt; — With many SMBs being service-oriented, accurately capturing billable hours is critical to your success. Accounting for every minute at the proper rate and capturing all expenses is beyond critical; not doing so can cost company profits and possibly jobs. By automating your operations with a business management platform, you can &lt;em&gt;save&lt;/em&gt; thousands and &lt;em&gt;earn&lt;/em&gt; These solutions help ensure a company is getting paid what they are worth and that no money (or service) is left unaccounted for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selecting a business management platform can be a critical step in helping your SMB succeed. But it’s vital that you choose a solution that’s a great fit for today’s needs and that can scale with you as you grow. Do a little homework to select the proper business management platform for your company – one that combines project management and professional services automation (PSA) for growing SMBs can dramatically impact bottom lines and enable you to get back to living life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See how Vorex’s cloud-based business management platform can change your business, your life and your world. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorex.com/free-trial/&quot; title=&quot;Free Trial&quot;&gt;Try us out free for 14 days.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-02-27T19:42:00+00:00</pubDate>
          <link>/blog/can-business-management-software-prevent-failure/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/can-business-management-software-prevent-failure/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
